let questions = [
    {
        "numb": 1,
        "question": "Which type of microscope is especially useful for viewing thick structures? ",
        "answer": " a transmission electron microscope",
        "options": [
            " a transmission electron microscope",
            "a scanning electron microscopes",
            "an atomic force microscope",
            "a confocal scanning laser microscope",
            "a phase-contrast microscope"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 2,
        "question": "What is the correct name for the microscope lens located in the eyepiece ?",
        "answer": "ocular",
        "options": [
            "condenser",
            "ocular",
            " base",
            " binocular",
            "objective"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 3,
        "question": "Which of the following is best suited to get surface view of an object? ",
        "answer": "Scanning electron microscope (SEM);",
        "options": [
            "Transmission electron microscope (TEM);",
            "Scanning electron microscope (SEM);",
            "Phase contrast microscope",
            "SEM and TEM.",
            "Compound microscope"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 4,
        "question": "How is called the method that consists of collection of data through observation and experimentation, formulation and testing of hypothesis: ",
        "answer": "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 Scientific \t",
        "options": [
            "Scientific evidences & Empirical ",
            " Empirical ",
            "Scientific evidences ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 Scientific \t",
            "Facts"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 5,
        "question": "Which microscope has the highest magnification power?",
        "answer": "electron microscope",
        "options": [
            "light microscope",
            "electron microscope",
            "compound microscope",
            "optical microscope",
            "high power microscope"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 6,
        "question": "Process of what component distinguish prokaryotes from eukaryotes?",
        "answer": "incipient nucleus ",
        "options": [
            "cell membrane",
            "incipient nucleus ",
            " small vacuoles ",
            " smaller ribosomes",
            " cell wall"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 7,
        "question": "What will show red blood cells which are placed in 0.5% sodium chloride?",
        "answer": "Bursting",
        "options": [
            "Shrinking",
            "Turgidity",
            "Crenation",
            "Bursting",
            "Plasmolysis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 8,
        "question": "In a prokaryotic cell, the DNA is \u00e2\u20ac\u00a6",
        "answer": "\"naked\" and \"free-floating\"",
        "options": [
            "\"naked\" and \"free-floating\"",
            " have a complex nucleus",
            "wrapped around histone proteins",
            "\u00c2\u00a0lack membrane-bound compartments",
            "contained in the nucleus"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 9,
        "question": "Which of the following checkpoint is considered a restriction point?",
        "answer": " G1 checkpoint",
        "options": [
            " G1 checkpoint",
            "M checkpoint",
            "None of the above",
            "G2 checkpoint",
            "S checkpoint"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 10,
        "question": "During which of the following stages of mitosis the individual chromosomes become distinct through the light microscope?",
        "answer": "Prophase",
        "options": [
            "Telophase",
            "Anaphase",
            " Metaphase ",
            "Prophase",
            "Interphase"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 11,
        "question": " Which of the following statements is wrong? ",
        "answer": "chromatin uncoils to form chromosomes",
        "options": [
            "chromosomes can be seen just as cell division is about to occur",
            "chromatin is made up of the DNA double helix and associated proteins",
            "chromatin is found within the nucleus",
            "chromatin uncoils to form chromosomes",
            "each species generally has a characteristic number of chromosomes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 12,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true about Mendel?",
        "answer": "His ideas about genetics apply equally to plants and animals.",
        "options": [
            " His experiments have a small sampling size.",
            " His discoveries concerning genetic inheritance were generally accepted by the scientific community when he published them during the mid-19th\u00c2\u00a0century",
            " Mendel initially selected pea plants with same character",
            "His ideas about genetics apply equally to plants and animals.",
            "He believed that genetic traits of parents will usually blend in their children."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 13,
        "question": "Test cross determines",
        "answer": " the genotype of F2\u00c2\u00a0plant",
        "options": [
            " the genotype of F2\u00c2\u00a0plant",
            " whether two traits are linked or not",
            " the phenotype of F2\u00c2\u00a0plant",
            " number of alleles in a gene",
            " whether the two species will breed successfully or not"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 14,
        "question": "The type of inheritance shown when a red-flowering plant is crossed with a white-flowering plant and only pink-flowering plants are produced is _____.",
        "answer": "incomplete dominance",
        "options": [
            "codominance",
            "interbreeding",
            " dominance",
            "polygenic inheritance",
            "incomplete dominance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 15,
        "question": "What is a gene called?",
        "answer": "A Section of DNA that codes for a protein or RNA molecule.",
        "options": [
            "A Section of DNA that codes for a protein or RNA molecule.",
            "A Regulatory Sequence",
            " A Chromosome Carrier",
            " An Exon\u00c2\u00a0",
            " A piece of clothing that is placed upon the bipedal legs of human."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 16,
        "question": "Two men who are identical twins marry two women who are also identical twins. Each couple has a daughter. The daughters are more genetically similar than is usual for first cousins.Which statement describes the degree of genetic similarity between the daughters?",
        "answer": "\u00c2\u00a0 They are genetically different from each other due to independent assortment in meiosis.",
        "options": [
            "They are genetically different from each other due to random mutation.",
            " They are not genetical, because got different spontaneous  mutations during gametogenesis  ",
            "They are genetically identical because they share the same parental gene pool",
            "\u00c2\u00a0 They are genetically different from each other due to independent assortment in meiosis.",
            "They are genetically identical because random mutation is rare."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 17,
        "question": "A classical example of codominance is :",
        "answer": " Blood Type AB ",
        "options": [
            " Blood Type O ",
            " Blood type O and A",
            "Blood Type A ",
            "Blood Type B ",
            " Blood Type AB "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 18,
        "question": "A recessive allele t is responsible for a condition called phenylketonouria. A man who has this disease marries a woman who doesn\u00e2\u20ac\u2122t have this disease. One of their four children has the disorder. What are possible genotypes of the man and woman?",
        "answer": "the father is tt, mother is Tt",
        "options": [
            "the father is Tt, mother is TT                                                  ",
            "both parents are tt",
            "the father is tt, mother is Tt",
            "both parents are TT ",
            "the father is tt, the mother is TT                                      "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 19,
        "question": "What is the phenotypic ratio in case of dominant epistasis?",
        "answer": "(9:3:3:1) ",
        "options": [
            "(9:3:3:1) ",
            "09:07",
            "12:03:04",
            "09:03:04",
            "9:4:3:1"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 20,
        "question": "What mode of inheritance involves more than two forms of gene giving rise to a repertoire of phenotypes?",
        "answer": "Incomplete &complete dominance",
        "options": [
            "Incomplete dominance",
            "Complete dominance",
            "Incomplete &complete dominance",
            "Multiple allelism",
            "Codominance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 21,
        "question": "How is pleiotropy different from polygenic inheritance?",
        "answer": "A single gene can exhibit multiple expressions",
        "options": [
            "A single gene exhibits only a single expression",
            "Multiple genes control a single character",
            "Two genes exhibit a single character",
            "The genes can not control characters ",
            "A single gene can exhibit multiple expressions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 22,
        "question": "Which of the following is a chromosomal abnormality that involves an extra copy of chromosome 21? ",
        "answer": "Down syndrome ",
        "options": [
            "Down syndrome ",
            "Edwards syndrome",
            "Klinefelter syndrome",
            "Patau syndrome ",
            "Turner syndrome "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 23,
        "question": "How many autosomal chromosomes do you normally inherit from a single parent?",
        "answer": "22",
        "options": [
            "22",
            "23",
            "46",
            "45",
            "1"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 24,
        "question": "A human genetic defect that is caused by nondisjunction of the sex chromosome is :",
        "answer": "\u00c2\u00a0 Turner syndrome",
        "options": [
            "Color blindness",
            "Sickle cell anemia ",
            "Edward\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s syndrome",
            "\u00c2\u00a0 Turner syndrome",
            "Down syndrome "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 25,
        "question": "Which of the following describes the genetic pattern of Duchenne muscular dystrophy?",
        "answer": "X-linked recessive",
        "options": [
            "Chromosomal defect",
            "Mitochondrial DNA mutation",
            "X-linked recessive",
            "Autosomal dominant ",
            "X-linked dominant"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 26,
        "question": "Which one of the following is not an example of aneuploidy?",
        "answer": "Phenylketonuria",
        "options": [
            "Turner\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s syndrome",
            "Edwards\u00e2\u20ac\u2122  syndrome ",
            "Down\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s syndrome",
            "Klinefelter\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s syndrome",
            "Phenylketonuria"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 27,
        "question": "By which of the following methods, a pattern of inheritance can be traced in a family?",
        "answer": "pedigree analysis",
        "options": [
            "nuclear analysis",
            "chromosomal analysis",
            "pedigree analysis",
            "nuclear analysis & cytoplasm analysis",
            "cytoplasm analysis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 28,
        "question": "RNA contains which bases?",
        "answer": "thymine, guanine, cytosine, uracil",
        "options": [
            " adenine, thymine, guanine, cytosine, uracil",
            "thymine, guanine, cytosine, uracil",
            " adenine, guanine, cytosine, uracil",
            "adenine, thymine, guanine, cytosine",
            "thymine,  histone, nucleotide, adenine.  "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 29,
        "question": "Which one is mostly transcribed ?",
        "answer": "single copy of DNA  sequence",
        "options": [
            "single copy of DNA  sequence",
            "highly repetitive DNA sequence",
            "only RNA  sequence",
            "middle repetitive DNA & RNA sequences",
            "middle repetitive DNA sequence"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 30,
        "question": "How many percentage of Cytosine in the DNA, if a double stranded DNA has 20% Adenine? ",
        "answer": "30%",
        "options": [
            "30%",
            "90%",
            "40%",
            "10%",
            "15%"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 31,
        "question": "What did Hershey and Chase use for labeling  T2 phage in their experiment?",
        "answer": "radioisotopes",
        "options": [
            "radioisotopes",
            "metal",
            "sugar",
            "polyscaharids",
            "nonmetal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 32,
        "question": "A child is diagnosed with a rare genetic disease. Neither parent has the disease. How might the child have inherited the disorder?",
        "answer": "The disorder is sex linked and inherited only from the father.",
        "options": [
            "The disorder is sex linked and inherited only from the father.",
            "The disorder could occur only as a mutation in the child  because neither parent had the disease. ",
            "The disorder is sex linked and inherited only from the mother",
            "The disorder is dominant and was carried by a parent.",
            "The disorder is recessive and carried by both parents  as carriers "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 33,
        "question": "Messenger RNA (mRNA) can be best described as:",
        "answer": " A Short-lived RNA molecule that carries encoded information, transcribed from DNA.",
        "options": [
            " A Chromosome that is only present in prokaryotes and is involved in DNA synthesis",
            "The Atom that carries information to an RNA template",
            " A Short-lived RNA molecule that carries encoded information, transcribed from DNA.",
            " A really cool way of rewriting RNA",
            "A Molecule that has no life and is basically the news reporter of the cellular environment."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 34,
        "question": "Albinism is a genetic disease that results in incomplete metabolism of ?",
        "answer": "Tyrosine",
        "options": [
            "Cystine",
            "Histidine",
            "Hexoaminidase A ",
            "Alanine",
            "Tyrosine"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 35,
        "question": "Which of the following is a modern method of studying human genetics and diagnosing hereditary diseases? ",
        "answer": "Cytogenetic Testing.\u00c2\u00a0",
        "options": [
            " Computerized tomography (CT)\u00c2\u00a0scan  ",
            " Blood test ",
            "Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) ",
            "Cytogenetic Testing.\u00c2\u00a0",
            "X-ray "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 36,
        "question": "Which one of the following is the reason of Tay-Sachs disease ?",
        "answer": "deficiency of Hexoaminidase A  ",
        "options": [
            "deficiency of alpha galactosidase ",
            "due to deficiency of tyrosinase ",
            "due to deficiency of glucoserebrosidase ",
            "deficiency of Hexoaminidase A  & B",
            "deficiency of Hexoaminidase A  "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 37,
        "question": "Phenylketonuria (PKU)  is a genetic disorder caused by a deficiency of an enzyme that converts phenylalanine to tyrosine.  Identify the correct statements regarding 'phenylketonuria':",
        "answer": "Missense mutation of the PAH gene  are frequently observed in PKU patients",
        "options": [
            "Phenylketonuria is autosomal dominant disease ",
            "PKU occurs due to mutation of HTT gene",
            "Treated PKU can lead to intellectual disability, seizures, behavioral problems, and mental disorders.",
            "Missense mutation of the PAH gene  are frequently observed in PKU patients",
            "All PKU patients do not respond to biopterin  treatment"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 38,
        "question": "During the amniocentesis  test How many days are required ?",
        "answer": "\u00c2\u00a0 3-4 weeks ",
        "options": [
            "1-2 days ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0 1-2 weeks",
            "7-8 weeks ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0 3-4 weeks ",
            " 5-6 days"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 39,
        "question": "What is the primary focus of medical parasitology?",
        "answer": "Study of parasites that infect humans",
        "options": [
            "Study of plant parasites",
            "Study of animal behavior",
            "Study of marine life",
            "Study of bacteria and viruses",
            "Study of parasites that infect humans"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 40,
        "question": "What structure lacks commonly in Protista?",
        "answer": "Cell wall",
        "options": [
            "organelles for locomotion",
            "Cell membrane",
            "Cell organelle",
            "Cell wall",
            "Cytoplasm"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 41,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic feature of protozoan?",
        "answer": "prokaryotic microorganisms",
        "options": [
            "prokaryotic microorganisms",
            "Contractile vacuole",
            "Pseudopodia",
            "Have no cell wall",
            "multiply asexually and sexually"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 42,
        "question": "Which of the following strategies is NOT commonly used for the control and prevention of parasitic infections?",
        "answer": "Antibiotic treatment",
        "options": [
            "Vector control",
            "Public health education",
            "Vaccination",
            "Improving sanitation",
            "Antibiotic treatment"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 43,
        "question": "Which of the following is a biological feature of Trichomonas vaginalis?",
        "answer": "It is a flagellated protozoan",
        "options": [
            "It is an intracellular parasite",
            "It has a cyst stage",
            "It causes disease primarily in the gastrointestinal tract",
            "It is a flagellated protozoan",
            "It is a spore-forming protozoan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 44,
        "question": "Which organ of trophozoite of Giardia lamblia serves as an attachment organ?   ",
        "answer": "parabasal body",
        "options": [
            " nuclei; ",
            "flagella; ",
            "parabasal body",
            "axostyle; ",
            "sucking disc; "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 45,
        "question": "What are the common symptoms of trichomoniasis in women?                                                                                                    ",
        "answer": " Itching and burning sensation in the genitals;",
        "options": [
            "Abdominal pain and nausea;",
            "Sore throat and fever; ",
            " Itching and burning sensation in the genitals;",
            "Rash and swollen lymph nodes; ",
            " coughing and shortness"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 46,
        "question": "Which of the following is a method for preventing Giardia lamblia infection? ",
        "answer": "Avoiding contaminated food and water ",
        "options": [
            " Using insect repellent ",
            " Vaccination ",
            "Avoiding contaminated soil",
            "Antibiotic treatment ",
            "Avoiding contaminated food and water "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 47,
        "question": "Which of the following belongs to the phylum Sarcomastigophora? ",
        "answer": "Trypanosoma cruzi ",
        "options": [
            "Balantidium coli ",
            "Taenia solium",
            "Plasmodium falciparum ",
            "Entamoeba histolytica ",
            "Trypanosoma cruzi "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 48,
        "question": " What is the vector transmitting Trypanosoma brucei to humans? ",
        "answer": " Tsetse fly ",
        "options": [
            " Tsetse fly ",
            " Lice",
            "Sand fly ",
            "Mosquito",
            " Flea "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 49,
        "question": "Which type of leishmaniasis affects the skin and is characterized by ulcers such as Oriental ulcer and Pentadrian ulcer?",
        "answer": "Cutaneous Leishmaniasis",
        "options": [
            "Visceral Leishmaniasis",
            "Cutaneous Leishmaniasis",
            "Mucosal Leishmaniasis",
            "Diffuse Cutaneous Leishmaniasis",
            "Mucocutaneous Leishmaniasis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 50,
        "question": "Which type of leishmaniasis is also known as \"Black Fever\" and primarily affects the internal organs like the spleen, liver, and bone marrow?",
        "answer": "Visceral Leishmaniasis",
        "options": [
            "Cutaneous Leishmaniasis",
            "Visceral Leishmaniasis",
            "Oriental Ulcer",
            "Mucocutaneous Leishmaniasis",
            "Dum-Dum Fever"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 51,
        "question": "Which medication is commonly used for the treatment of Chagas Disease caused by Trypanosoma cruzi?",
        "answer": "Nifurtimox",
        "options": [
            "Nifurtimox",
            "Penicillin",
            "Artemisinin-based combination therapy (ACT)",
            "Metronidazole",
            "Chloroquine"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 52,
        "question": "Which amoeba exhibits a trophozoite stage in its life cycle?",
        "answer": "  Entamoeba histolytica",
        "options": [
            "  Entamoeba histolytica",
            "  Balamuthia mandrillaris",
            "  Acanthamoeba spp.",
            "  Naegleria fowleri",
            "  Plasmodium vivax"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 53,
        "question": "What is the primary mode of transmission of Acanthamoeba spp. leading to human infection?",
        "answer": "  Contact lens contamination",
        "options": [
            "  Inhalation of cysts",
            "  Contact lens contamination",
            "  Blood transfusion",
            "  Ingestion of contaminated food",
            "  Skin contact with contaminated soil"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 54,
        "question": "What is the primary habitat of Naegleria fowleri in which it proliferates and is commonly found?",
        "answer": "  Freshwater lakes and rivers",
        "options": [
            "  Freshwater lakes and rivers",
            "  Human gastrointestinal tract",
            "  Domestic animals' fur",
            "  Ocean water",
            "  Soil and decaying vegetation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 55,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0Which of the following clinical features is associated with infection by Naegleria fowleri?",
        "answer": "\u00c2\u00a0   Meningitis ",
        "options": [
            "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0   Hepatitis",
            "  Gastroenteritis",
            "   Dermatitis",
            "\u00c2\u00a0   Meningitis ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0   Pneumonia "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 56,
        "question": "What is the primary drug of choice for the treatment of Naegleria fowleri infections?",
        "answer": "  Amphotericin B",
        "options": [
            "  Amphotericin B",
            "  Antifungal agents",
            "  Corticosteroids",
            "  Intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG)",
            "  Antimicrobial agents"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 57,
        "question": "Which of the following is a single-celled parasite that can cause malaria?",
        "answer": "Plasmodium",
        "options": [
            "Plasmodium",
            "Schistosoma",
            "Ascaris lumbricoides",
            "Taenia solium",
            " Giardia lamblia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 58,
        "question": "Which organ is primarily affected by the malaria parasite during the asexual stage of its life cycle?",
        "answer": " Liver",
        "options": [
            " Liver",
            "Stomach",
            "Lungs",
            "Heart",
            "Kidneys"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 59,
        "question": "Organisms with complex life cycles which include a mammalian host and an insect host and involves schizogony as part of the cycle belong to which phylum of Protozoa?",
        "answer": "  Apicomplexa",
        "options": [
            "  Sarcomastigophora",
            "  Microsporodia ",
            "  Labyinthomorpha",
            "  Apicomplexa",
            "  Ciliophora  "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 60,
        "question": "What is the structure of Plasmodium vivax?",
        "answer": "   Sporozoan protozoan ",
        "options": [
            "   Sporozoan protozoan ",
            "  Amoeboid protozoan ",
            "  Helminth parasite",
            "  Flagellated protozoan ",
            "  Ciliated protozoan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 61,
        "question": "Which medication is commonly used to prevent relapses in Plasmodium vivax infections?",
        "answer": "  Primaquine",
        "options": [
            "  Chloroquine",
            "  Quinine",
            "  Primaquine",
            "  Artemisinin-based combination therapies (ACTs)",
            "  Penicillin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 62,
        "question": "Which biological feature is characteristic of members of Class Aconoidasida?",
        "answer": "They have complex life cycles with both sexual and asexual stages",
        "options": [
            "They do not require an intermediate host",
            "They are extracellular parasites",
            "They have complex life cycles with both sexual and asexual stages",
            "They form cysts in muscle tissue",
            "They primarily infect the respiratory system"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 63,
        "question": "Which clinical condition is most commonly associated with Toxoplasma gondii infection in immunocompromised individuals?",
        "answer": "Encephalitis",
        "options": [
            "Gastroenteritis",
            "Dermatitis",
            "Hepatitis",
            "Pneumonia",
            "Encephalitis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 64,
        "question": "Which population is at the highest risk for severe complications from Cryptosporidium parvum infection?",
        "answer": "Immunocompromised individuals",
        "options": [
            "Elderly individuals",
            "Children under 5 years",
            "Pregnant women",
            "Immunocompromised individuals",
            "Healthy adults"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 65,
        "question": "Which stage of Toxoplasma gondii is infectious to humans?",
        "answer": "Oocyst",
        "options": [
            "Oocyst",
            "Tachyzoite",
            "Sporozoite",
            "Bradyzoite",
            "Trophozoite"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 66,
        "question": "What is the primary method of prevention for Toxoplasma gondii infection in pregnant women?",
        "answer": "Avoiding contact with cat litter",
        "options": [
            "Wearing masks",
            "Avoiding contact with cat litter",
            "Drinking bottled water",
            "Using insect repellent",
            "Avoiding dairy products"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 67,
        "question": "What is the primary mode of transmission of Balantidium coli to humans?",
        "answer": "Ingestion of contaminated food or water",
        "options": [
            "Sexual contact",
            "Inhalation of spores",
            "Direct skin contact with contaminated soil",
            "Mosquito bites",
            "Ingestion of contaminated food or water"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 68,
        "question": "Which clinical symptom is commonly associated with Balantidium coli infection?",
        "answer": "Diarrhea",
        "options": [
            "Diarrhea",
            "Visual disturbances",
            "Joint pain",
            "Respiratory distress",
            "Rash"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 69,
        "question": "What is an effective measure for preventing Balantidium coli infection?",
        "answer": "Drinking only boiled or filtered water",
        "options": [
            "Drinking only boiled or filtered water",
            "Using insect repellent",
            "Getting vaccinated",
            "Wearing protective clothing",
            "Avoiding contact with infected animals"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 70,
        "question": "Which parasitic disease is known for causing liver damage and is transmitted through contaminated water?",
        "answer": "Schistosomiasis",
        "options": [
            "Malaria",
            "Leishmaniasis",
            "Toxoplasmosis",
            "Schistosomiasis",
            "Giardiasis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 71,
        "question": "What is the primary mode of transmission for Schistosoma species?",
        "answer": "Direct skin contact with contaminated water",
        "options": [
            " Ingestion of contaminated food",
            "Tick bites",
            "Inhalation of airborne spores",
            " Mosquito bites",
            "Direct skin contact with contaminated water"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 72,
        "question": "What is the most common diagnostic method for identifying intestinal helminth infections?",
        "answer": "Stool examination",
        "options": [
            "Saliva test",
            "Skin biopsy",
            "Urine analysis",
            "Blood smear",
            "Stool examination"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 73,
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the class Cestoda (tapeworms)?",
        "answer": "They are segmented and lack a digestive system",
        "options": [
            "They have a round body and live in freshwater",
            "They have an unsegmented body and complete digestive system",
            "They are segmented and lack a digestive system",
            "They are free-living and found in soil",
            "They have a coiled body and possess a radula"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 74,
        "question": "Echinococcus granulosus, a parasitic representative of tapeworms, causes which disease in humans?",
        "answer": "Hydatid disease",
        "options": [
            "Hydatid disease",
            "Filariasis",
            "Malaria",
            "Schistosomiasis",
            "Ascariasis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 75,
        "question": "Which of the following is a common clinical symptom of hydatid disease caused by Echinococcus granulosus?",
        "answer": "Formation of cysts in the liver and lungs",
        "options": [
            "Formation of cysts in the liver and lungs",
            "Acute diarrhea",
            "Skin rash",
            "Severe headaches",
            "Chronic cough"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 76,
        "question": "Which stage of Echinococcus granulosus is infective to intermediate hosts such as sheep and humans?",
        "answer": "Egg",
        "options": [
            "Egg",
            "Cysticercus",
            "Adult",
            "Miracidium",
            "Cercaria"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 77,
        "question": "What is a primary preventive measure for hydatid disease caused by Echinococcus granulosus?",
        "answer": "Regular deworming of dogs",
        "options": [
            "Regular deworming of dogs",
            "Avoiding consumption of undercooked meat",
            "Wearing protective clothing",
            "Using insect repellent",
            "Avoiding contact with freshwater bodies"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 78,
        "question": "Which parasitic roundworm is commonly known as the heartworm and affects dogs?",
        "answer": "Dirofilaria immitis",
        "options": [
            "Trichinella spiralis",
            "Wuchereria bancrofti",
            "Brugia malayi",
            "Dirofilaria immitis",
            "Enterobius vermicularis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 79,
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the life cycle of Schistosoma spp. is true?",
        "answer": "Larvae penetrate the skin of humans in contaminated water",
        "options": [
            "Transmission occurs through mosquito bites",
            "Intermediate host is the housefly",
            "Larvae penetrate the skin of humans in contaminated water",
            "Adults reside in the intestines and release eggs into feces",
            "Eggs are ingested through contaminated food"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 80,
        "question": "Which parasite has a life cycle involving freshwater snails as an intermediate host and infects humans through direct skin penetration?",
        "answer": "Schistosoma spp.",
        "options": [
            "Fasciolopsis buski",
            "Schistosoma spp.",
            "Fasciola hepatica",
            "Taenia solium",
            "Paragonimus westermani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 81,
        "question": "Which of the following Trematoda parasites is known to cause lung infections?",
        "answer": "Paragonimus westermani",
        "options": [
            "Schistosoma japonicum",
            "Fasciolopsis buski",
            "Fasciola hepatica",
            "Schistosoma mansoni",
            "Paragonimus westermani"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 82,
        "question": "What preventive measure can be taken to avoid infection by Paragonimus westermani?",
        "answer": "Avoid eating raw or undercooked freshwater crabs and crayfish",
        "options": [
            "Avoid eating raw or undercooked freshwater crabs and crayfish",
            "Drink only boiled or bottled water",
            "Wear protective clothing",
            "Use insect repellent",
            "Avoid swimming in freshwater bodies"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 83,
        "question": "What helminthic infection  is cause of an elephantiasis?",
        "answer": " Wuchereria bancrofti",
        "options": [
            " Fasciola hepatica",
            "Taenia solium",
            " Trichinella spiralis",
            "",
            " Wuchereria bancrofti"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 84,
        "question": "By what infection is presented lymphangitis, lymphadenitis and chyluria clinical manifestations? ",
        "answer": " Echinococcus granulosus",
        "options": [
            "Loa loa",
            "Brugia malayi",
            "Dirofilaria immitis ",
            " Echinococcus granulosus",
            "Mansonella ozzardi "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 85,
        "question": "Where are  primarily found the pinworms in the body?",
        "answer": "Wuchereria bancrofti",
        "options": [
            "Under the skin",
            " Lungs",
            "Wuchereria bancrofti",
            " Colon/rectum",
            " Intestine"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 86,
        "question": "During observing the patients with ascariasis what can cause the larval stage of Ascaris lumbricoides?",
        "answer": "Intestinal obstruction",
        "options": [
            "Intussusception",
            "Pneumonitis",
            "Malnutrition",
            "Intestinal obstruction",
            "Coughing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 87,
        "question": "Which of the following diseases is NOT typically associated with tick transmission?",
        "answer": "Japanese encephalitis",
        "options": [
            "Japanese encephalitis",
            "West Nile encephalitis",
            "Russian spring-summer encephalitis",
            "Tick-borne encephalitis",
            "Lyme disease"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 88,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true regarding the epidemiologic significance of arthropods?",
        "answer": "Many arthropods act as vectors for disease transmission.",
        "options": [
            "Arthropods are exclusively herbivorous.",
            "Many arthropods act as vectors for disease transmission.",
            "Arthropods do not harbor parasites.",
            "Arthropods do not cause allergic reactions.",
            "Arthropods have a complex life cycle without metamorphosis."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 89,
        "question": "Which of the following diseases is primarily transmitted by ticks and can lead to encephalitis?",
        "answer": "West Nile encephalitis",
        "options": [
            "West Nile encephalitis",
            "Malaria",
            "Lyme disease",
            "Japanese encephalitis",
            "Rocky Mountain spotted fever"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 90,
        "question": "Which disease, transmitted by ticks, is known for causing encephalitis predominantly in Russia during the spring and summer seasons?",
        "answer": "Russian spring-summer encephalitis",
        "options": [
            "Zika virus infection",
            "Lyme disease",
            "Japanese encephalitis",
            "Russian spring-summer encephalitis",
            "West Nile encephalitis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 91,
        "question": "Mosquitoes must have following necessity to complete their life cycle?",
        "answer": "Water",
        "options": [
            "Water",
            "Intermediate host",
            "Vector",
            "pupa",
            ""
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 92,
        "question": "What is the primary vector responsible for transmitting Dengue virus?",
        "answer": "Aedes mosquito",
        "options": [
            "Culex mosquito",
            "Tsetse fly",
            "Phlebotomine fly",
            "Aedes mosquito",
            "Anopheles mosquito"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 93,
        "question": "Which symptom is characteristic of severe Dengue fever (Dengue hemorrhagic fever)?",
        "answer": "Bleeding tendencies",
        "options": [
            "Profuse sweating",
            "Severe headache",
            "Bleeding tendencies",
            "Rash",
            "Joint pain"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 94,
        "question": "What is incorrect about Dengue fever? ",
        "answer": "has an incubation period of 2-3 weeks",
        "options": [
            "is caused by a flavivirus",
            "characteristically causes severe myalgia",
            "has an incubation period of 2-3 weeks",
            "is spread by the vector Aedes aegypti",
            "is more likely to cause bleeding  in patients previously infected by a Dengue virus"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 95,
        "question": "Which measure is most effective for preventing Dengue fever?",
        "answer": "Using mosquito repellent",
        "options": [
            "Wearing long-sleeved clothing",
            "Using mosquito repellent",
            "Vaccination",
            "Quarantine of infected individuals",
            "Indoor residual spraying with insecticides"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 96,
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a common vector for encephalitis?",
        "answer": "Flies",
        "options": [
            "Mites",
            "Mosquitoes",
            "Flies",
            "Ticks",
            "Fleas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 97,
        "question": "In which location are bed bugs commonly found in infested environments?",
        "answer": "In cracks and crevices of furniture and walls",
        "options": [
            "In cracks and crevices of furniture and walls",
            "Underneath rocks",
            "Inside fruit",
            "Buried in soil",
            "In tree canopies"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 98,
        "question": "Which is a common symptom of bed bug bites in humans?",
        "answer": "Itchy welts or papules",
        "options": [
            "Severe headache",
            "Joint swelling",
            "Itchy welts or papules",
            "Rash with blisters",
            "Muscle pain"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 99,
        "question": "Which characteristic defines insects of the order Siphonaptera, such as fleas?",
        "answer": "They have piercing-sucking mouthparts",
        "options": [
            "They have chewing mouthparts",
            "They are known for swarming behavior",
            "They have piercing-sucking mouthparts",
            "They are primarily herbivorous",
            "They undergo complete metamorphosis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 100,
        "question": "Which measure is most effective for preventing flea infestations in pets?",
        "answer": "Regular grooming and inspection of pets",
        "options": [
            "Indoor residual spraying with insecticides",
            "Vaccination of pets",
            "Regular grooming and inspection of pets",
            "Avoiding contact with wild rodents",
            "Use of mosquito nets"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 101,
        "question": "Which of the following reasoning uses general principle to predict specific results? ",
        "answer": "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 Deductive",
        "options": [
            "Inductive & Hypothetico-deductive",
            "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 Deductive",
            " Hypothetico-deductive",
            "Inductive and deductive ",
            "Inductive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 102,
        "question": "A procedure design to test the hypothesis is known as ?",
        "answer": "Experiment",
        "options": [
            "Theory ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0  Idea",
            "Law",
            " Dogma",
            "Experiment"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 103,
        "question": "What is the name of the region where double-stranded single circular DNA is found in the prokaryotic cell?",
        "answer": "Nucleoid",
        "options": [
            "Nucleoid",
            "Protonucleus",
            "Nucleoplasm",
            "Nucleus",
            "Cytoplasm"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 104,
        "question": "When looking at a specimen on your slide, you should always start with the ____?",
        "answer": "low objective lens",
        "options": [
            "super extra high power lens",
            "medium objective lens",
            "extra high power lens",
            "low objective lens",
            "high objective lens"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 105,
        "question": "Which of these is a characteristic of prokaryotic cells?",
        "answer": " All of these",
        "options": [
            "Presence of 70S ribosomes",
            "Absence of cell organelles",
            "Absence of nucleus",
            "Lack a true membrane-bound nucleus",
            " All of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 106,
        "question": "How is called the solution which has equal amount of solute and solvent in and out of a cell? ",
        "answer": " isotonic",
        "options": [
            " hypotonic",
            " hypertonic",
            " isotonic",
            "hypertonic & hypotonic",
            "isotonic & hypertonic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 107,
        "question": "Which of the following describes an observable occurrence in nature that appears to always be true ?",
        "answer": "Law",
        "options": [
            "  Idea",
            "Experiment",
            "Theory",
            "Law",
            "Hypothesis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 108,
        "question": "In meiosis, crossing-over occurs:",
        "answer": "only during prophase I and involves exchange between chromatids of homologous  chromosomes.",
        "options": [
            " only during prophase I and involves exchange of chromosome fragments between sister chromatids.",
            "during prophase I and II and involves exchange of chromosome fragments between sister chromatids.",
            "only during prophase I and involves exchange between chromatids of homologous  chromosomes.",
            "during prophase I and II and involves exchange of chromosome fragments between all four chromatids.",
            " during prophase II and involves exchange of chromosome fragments between sister chromatids."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 109,
        "question": "Condensation of chromosomes occurs in",
        "answer": "Prophase I",
        "options": [
            "Anaphase",
            "Prophase I",
            "Interphase",
            " Metaphase ",
            "Prophase II"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 110,
        "question": "Which spindle fiber will lengthen, thereby pushing the chromosomes to the middle of metaphase? ",
        "answer": "polar spindle fibers",
        "options": [
            "centriolar fibers",
            "polar spindle fibers",
            "aster fibers",
            "centromeric spindle fibers",
            "centrosomes (MTOC) (MTOC- Microtubule-organizing centers)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 111,
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct sequence of mitotic phases?",
        "answer": "prophase, metaphase, telophase, anaphase",
        "options": [
            "anaphase, prophase, metaphase, telophase",
            "prophase, anaphase, metaphase, telophase",
            "prophase, metaphase, telophase, anaphase",
            "metaphase, anaphase, telophase, prophase",
            "prophase, metaphase, anaphase, telophase"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 112,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0If both genotype and phenotype shows the same ratios of 1:2:1 in the F2\u00c2\u00a0generation, it shows",
        "answer": " incomplete dominance in monohybrid cross",
        "options": [
            " monohybrid cross",
            " co-dominance",
            " dihybrid cross",
            " incomplete dominance in monohybrid cross",
            " complete dominance in monohybrid cross"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 113,
        "question": "A represents the dominant allele and a represents the recessive allele of a pair. If, in 1000 offspring, 500 are aa and 500 are of some other genotype, which of the following are most probably the genotypes of the parents? ",
        "answer": "Aa and Aa ",
        "options": [
            " Aa and aa ",
            " AA and Aa ",
            "Aa and Aa ",
            " AA and aa",
            "aa and aa"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 114,
        "question": "What is the maximum number of alleles that monohybrid cross can consider?",
        "answer": "2",
        "options": [
            "8",
            "10",
            "4",
            "6",
            "2"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 115,
        "question": "The monohybrid phenotypic and genotypic ratio is same in the case of __________",
        "answer": "Incomplete dominance",
        "options": [
            "Codominance",
            "Multiple allele",
            "Normal dominance recessive relation",
            " Dominant allele",
            "Incomplete dominance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 116,
        "question": "Considering a dihybrid cross, what is the probability of the progeny being heterozygous at both the alleles?",
        "answer": " 4/16",
        "options": [
            " 4/16",
            " 7/16",
            " 1/16",
            " 3/16",
            " 9/16"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 117,
        "question": "In case of codominance product is  ________",
        "answer": "Produced from both the alleles",
        "options": [
            "Produced from both the alleles",
            " Produced from one allele",
            "Incompletely produced from both alleles",
            "Recessive alelle",
            " None are functional"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 118,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0Which of the following ratio shows complementary gene interaction?",
        "answer": " 9:7",
        "options": [
            " 9:7",
            "03:01",
            " 15:1",
            " 1:2:1",
            " 9:3:3:1"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 119,
        "question": "In crossing a homozygous recessive with a heterozygote, what is the chance of getting an offspring with the homozygous recessive phenotype?",
        "answer": "50%",
        "options": [
            "50%",
            "25%",
            "0%",
            "100%",
            "75%"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 120,
        "question": "Which of the following is a human chromosomal syndrome caused by genomic abnormalities?",
        "answer": " Turner syndrome",
        "options": [
            " Cystic fibrosis",
            " Sickle cell anemia",
            " Duchenne muscular dystrophy ",
            " Hemophilia",
            " Turner syndrome"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 121,
        "question": "A red flowered plant (RR) is bred with a white flowered plant (rr) and the F1 generation has pink flowers (Rr). This is a example of",
        "answer": "Incomplete dominance",
        "options": [
            " polyspermy",
            " segregation",
            "Incomplete dominance",
            " co-dominance",
            " genetic mutation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 122,
        "question": "Which of the following human diseases is least likely  to be caused by aneuploidy?",
        "answer": " Achondroplasia",
        "options": [
            "Patau syndrome",
            " Klinefelter syndrome",
            "\u00c2\u00a0 Down syndrome",
            " Achondroplasia",
            "Turner syndrome"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 123,
        "question": "Down's syndrome can be caused by ___",
        "answer": " an extra chromosome 21 ",
        "options": [
            " a missing chromosome 18 ",
            " a missing chromosome 21\u00c2\u00a0",
            "an extra chromosome 19 ",
            " an extra chromosome 18 ",
            " an extra chromosome 21 "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 124,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0 Which of the following trisomy karyotypes has the mildest effect on human development?",
        "answer": " 47,XXX",
        "options": [
            " 47,XXX",
            "47,XX,+13",
            " 47,XY,+18",
            "47,XXY",
            "47,XY,+21"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 125,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0 What is the main symptom of Duchenne muscular dystrophy?",
        "answer": "Muscle weakness",
        "options": [
            "Muscle weakness",
            "Skin rash ",
            "Hearing loss ",
            " Cognitive impairment ",
            " Vision loss "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 126,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0An X linked recessive gene would appear to __________________",
        "answer": "Expressed mostly in men",
        "options": [
            " Be expressed in both males and females equally",
            "Skip generations",
            "Be lethal",
            "Expressed mostly in men",
            " Gradually degrade"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 127,
        "question": "Hemophilic  man marries woman having no history of the disease in her pedigree. What is the chance that a hemophilic son is born to them?",
        "answer": "0%",
        "options": [
            "50%",
            "0%",
            "25%",
            "75%",
            "5%"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 128,
        "question": "What type of bond forms between Complementary base pairs?",
        "answer": "Hydrogen",
        "options": [
            " Covalent",
            " Ionic",
            "Philial",
            "Hydrogen",
            " Interkinetic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 129,
        "question": "To understand the structure of RNA polymerase, researchers employed what technique to view this enzyme?",
        "answer": "X-ray crystallography",
        "options": [
            "PCR amplification",
            " Gas Chromatography",
            "Hardy-Weinberg equilibrium",
            "X-ray crystallography",
            "Gel Electrophoresis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 130,
        "question": "In analyzing the number of different bases in a DNA sample, which result would be consistent with the base-pairing rules?",
        "answer": "ATTC=TAAG",
        "options": [
            " A = G",
            "CAGT=TGAC",
            " G = T",
            "ATTC=TAAG",
            "AG=GA"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 131,
        "question": "Antiparallel strands of a DNA molecule means that:",
        "answer": "the phosphate groups at the start  of two DNA strands are in opposite position (pole)",
        "options": [
            "the phosphate groups of two DNA strands, at their ends, share the same position",
            " one strand turns anti-clockwise",
            "the phosphate groups at the start  of two DNA strands are in opposite position (pole)",
            "one strand turns clockwise",
            "both strands turn in one direction"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 132,
        "question": "Damage of structural gene \u00e2\u20ac\u201c area of DNA molecule took place. But replacement of amino acid did not happen because afterwards damage was liquidated. What process liquidated mutation",
        "answer": "reparation",
        "options": [
            "replication",
            "transcription",
            "opposite transcription",
            "reparation",
            "translation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 133,
        "question": "In DNA molecular there is 30% deoxyadenosinmonophosphate. How many deoxyguaninmonophosphate are there in this fragment?",
        "answer": "20%",
        "options": [
            "50%",
            "60%",
            "40%",
            "30%",
            "20%"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 134,
        "question": "Male to male transmission is a key feature of which pattern of inheritance?",
        "answer": "Y-linked recessive",
        "options": [
            "X-linked recessive",
            "Y-linked recessive",
            "Autosomal dominant",
            "Autosomal recessive",
            "X-linked dominant"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 135,
        "question": "Which of the following is a recessive autosomal hereditary disease? ",
        "answer": " Albinism ",
        "options": [
            "Huntington's disease ",
            " Albinism ",
            " Polydactyly",
            "Color blindness",
            " Achondroplasia "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 136,
        "question": "Cystic fibrosis (CF) is an inherited disease. How is CF passed down through families?",
        "answer": "Both parents are carriers of the CF gene",
        "options": [
            "One grandparent &one parent are carriers of CF gene ",
            "One parent is a carrier of the CF gene",
            "One grandparent is a carrier of the CF gene",
            "Parents are not carriers of CF gene ",
            "Both parents are carriers of the CF gene"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 137,
        "question": "Which disease in treated in part by a low-phenylalanine diet?\u00c2\u00a0",
        "answer": "Phenylketonouria       ",
        "options": [
            "Cystic Fibrosis ",
            " Color blindness",
            "Phenylketonouria       ",
            "Tay-Sach\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s desease           ",
            "Albinism                "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 138,
        "question": "Which of the following is a dominant autosomal hereditary disease? ",
        "answer": " Polydactyly ",
        "options": [
            "Tay-Sachs disease ",
            "Albinism ",
            " Cystic fibrosis ",
            " Polydactyly ",
            " Color blindness"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 139,
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the concept of a host in parasitology?",
        "answer": " An organism that is infected with a parasite and suffers from that relationship.",
        "options": [
            "  An organism that is capable of transmitting a parasite to other organisms.",
            "  An organism that is found in the environment and serves as a reservoir for parasites.",
            " An organism that is infected with a parasite and suffers from that relationship.",
            " An organism that is immune to the effects of a parasite and therefore does not suffer from infection.",
            "An organism that is infected with a parasite and suffers from that relationship."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 140,
        "question": "What factor prevents the stomach from being colonized by most protozoan parasites?",
        "answer": "Digestive enzymes",
        "options": [
            "Bile",
            "Absorption",
            "Deletion",
            "Peristalsis ",
            "Digestive enzymes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 141,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic feature of pr\u00d0\u00betozoans",
        "answer": " cell membrane as an outer body covering",
        "options": [
            " contractile vacuole",
            " binary fission",
            " pseudopodia",
            "Flagella",
            " cell membrane as an outer body covering"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 142,
        "question": "Protozoan have several types of vacuoles.Which of the following is true about a contractile vacuole?",
        "answer": "it maintains osmotic balance by continuous water expulsion",
        "options": [
            "it creates sites of food digestion",
            "it is responsible for \twater circulation",
            "it maintains osmotic balance by continuous water expulsion",
            "it contains specific enzymes that perform various functions",
            "None of stated"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 143,
        "question": "Which of the following statements true about the life cycle of Giardia lamblia?",
        "answer": " Giardia lamblia has a simple, direct life cycle that involves only one host species. ",
        "options": [
            " Giardia lamblia has a free-living stage that is not dependent on a host for survival.",
            " Giardia lamblia has an indirect life cycle and requires a vector, such as a mosquito, for transmission. ",
            "Giardia lamblia has a complex life cycle that involves multiple intermediate and definitive hosts.",
            " Giardia lamblia has a simple, direct life cycle that involves only one host species. ",
            "Giardia lamblia has a direct life cycle and can only be transmitted through direct contact with an infected host."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 144,
        "question": "Which of the following statements accurately describes the life cycle of Trichomonas vaginalis?",
        "answer": "Trophozoite stage, cyst stage, and sexual reproduction. ",
        "options": [
            "Trophozoite stage, cyst stage, and sexual reproduction. ",
            " Trophozoite stage, gametocyte stage, and asexual reproduction.",
            " Cyst stage, sporozoite stage, and sexual reproduction. ",
            " Gametocyte stage, zygote stage, and sporozoite stage. ",
            " Trophozoite stage, sporozoite stage, and asexual reproduction. "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 145,
        "question": "What is the clinical manifestation of giardiasis caused by Giardia lamblia? ",
        "answer": "Diarrhea ",
        "options": [
            "Diarrhea ",
            " Heart failure",
            " Malaria ",
            "  Lung abscess",
            "Liver abscess"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 146,
        "question": "Which drug is commonly used to treat infections caused by Trichomonas vaginalis?",
        "answer": "Metronidazole",
        "options": [
            "Ivermectin",
            "Metronidazole",
            "Chloroquine",
            "Ciprofloxacin",
            "Amoxicillin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 147,
        "question": "What is the phylum that Trypanosoma cruzi and Trypanosoma brucei belong to? ",
        "answer": "Sarcomastigophora ",
        "options": [
            " Apicomplexa ",
            " Ciliophora ",
            "Sarcomastigophora ",
            " Microsporidia",
            " Myxozoa "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 148,
        "question": "What is the vector  transmitting Trypanosoma cruzi to humans?  ",
        "answer": " Triatomine bug",
        "options": [
            " Triatomine bug",
            "\u00c2\u00a0 Tsetse fly ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0 Lice",
            " Mosquito ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0  Flea "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 149,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 What is the vector  transmission of Leishmania parasites?",
        "answer": "  Sand flies ",
        "options": [
            "  Sand flies ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0  Fleas ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0  Lice",
            " Mosquito ",
            " Ticks "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 150,
        "question": "What is a primary distinguishing feature of Trypanosoma brucei compared to Trypanosoma cruzi?",
        "answer": "Trypanosoma brucei is transmitted by the tsetse fly, while Trypanosoma cruzi is transmitted by triatomine bugs",
        "options": [
            "Trypanosoma brucei infects humans through the fecal matter of a kissing bug",
            "Both have identical pathogenesis in humans",
            "Trypanosoma brucei is transmitted by the tsetse fly, while Trypanosoma cruzi is transmitted by triatomine bugs",
            "Trypanosoma brucei completes its entire life cycle in humans",
            "Trypanosoma brucei has a kinetoplast absent in Trypanosoma cruzi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 151,
        "question": "Which of the following drugs is primarily used to treat acute Chagas disease caused by Trypanosoma cruzi?",
        "answer": "Benznidazole",
        "options": [
            "Ivermectin",
            "Azithromycin",
            "Quinine",
            "Benznidazole",
            "Amphotericin B"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 152,
        "question": "#REF!",
        "answer": "\u00c2\u00a0 The cyst is ingested by the host, excysts in the intestine, and releases trophozoites that invade the colon and form cysts. ",
        "options": [
            "\u00c2\u00a0 The cyst is ingested by the host, excysts in the intestine, and releases trophozoites that invade the colon and form cysts. ",
            "  The trophozoite is ingested by the host, encysts in the intestine, and releases cysts that invade the colon and form trophozoites. ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 The trophozoite is ingested by the host, encysts in the stomach, and releases cysts that are shed in the feces.",
            "\u00c2\u00a0  The cyst is ingested by the host, excysts in the stomach, and releases trophozoites that invade the liver and form cysts. ",
            "  The trophozoite is ingested by the host, invades the liver, and forms cysts that are shed in the feces. "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 153,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 Which of the following is not a biological feature of free-living amoebae? ",
        "answer": "They are obligate intracellular parasites ",
        "options": [
            "They are obligate intracellular parasites ",
            "  They can form cysts in adverse conditions ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0  They are found in soil and water ",
            " They can phagocytose other organisms",
            "  They are unicellular organisms "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 154,
        "question": " Which of the following parasite can cause granulomatous amoebic encephalitis (GAE)? ",
        "answer": "  Acanthamoeba spp.",
        "options": [
            "   Giardia lamblia",
            "  Trypanosoma cruzi ",
            " Trichomonas vaginalis",
            "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 Entamoeba histolytic ",
            "  Acanthamoeba spp."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 155,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 Which of the following amoebae can cause severe brain infection?",
        "answer": " Naegleria fowleri ",
        "options": [
            " Giardia lamblia",
            "\u00c2\u00a0  Entamoeba histolytica",
            "  Trypanosoma cruzi",
            " Naegleria fowleri ",
            "   Trichomonas vaginalis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 156,
        "question": "Which of the following is a crucial step in preventing the transmission of amoebas such as Naegleria fowleri and Acanthamoeba spp.?",
        "answer": " Chlorinating swimming pools and hot tubs",
        "options": [
            " Proper use of antibiotics",
            " Oral rehydration therapy",
            " Chlorinating swimming pools and hot tubs",
            " Regular deworming of pets",
            " Avoiding contact with infected animals"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 157,
        "question": "Which characteristic(s) are associated with parasites of the Class Aconoidasida?",
        "answer": " Formation of spores for transmission",
        "options": [
            " Preference for infecting humans directly without vectors",
            " Presence of flagella for locomotion",
            " Lack of association with diseases like malaria",
            " Involvement in causing amoebic infections",
            " Formation of spores for transmission"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 158,
        "question": "Which symptoms are typically associated with Malaria?",
        "answer": " Fever and chills",
        "options": [
            " Joint pain and headaches",
            " Vision disturbances and dizziness",
            " Cough and chest pain",
            " Skin rashes and irritations",
            " Fever and chills"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 159,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0 Which of the following is a common clinical feature of Plasmodium falciparum infection?",
        "answer": " Headache ",
        "options": [
            " Joint pain",
            "\u00c2\u00a0  Jaundice ",
            "  Cough ",
            " Headache ",
            " Rash "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 160,
        "question": " Which of the following is a potential complication of severe Plasmodium falciparum infection?",
        "answer": "  Liver failure ",
        "options": [
            " Pulmonary embolism ",
            " Hearing loss",
            "  Vision loss ",
            "  Kidney stones ",
            "  Liver failure "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 161,
        "question": "Which diagnostic method is commonly used to detect Malaria in endemic areas with limited resources?",
        "answer": " Rapid diagnostic tests (RDTs) for parasite antigens",
        "options": [
            " PCR (Polymerase Chain Reaction) testing",
            " Serological testing for antibodies",
            " ELISA (Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay)",
            " Microscopic examination of urine samples",
            " Rapid diagnostic tests (RDTs) for parasite antigens"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 162,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0 Who  is the   definitive  host of Toxoplasma gondii? ",
        "answer": "  Cats ",
        "options": [
            "\u00c2\u00a0  Dogs ",
            "  Cats ",
            "   Reptiles",
            "  human",
            "\u00c2\u00a0  Birds"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 163,
        "question": "Which stage of the life cycle of Toxoplasma gondii is infectious for humans?",
        "answer": "Oocyst ",
        "options": [
            "Oocyst ",
            " Schizont",
            " Tachyzoite ",
            " Bradyzoite",
            " Sporozoite "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 164,
        "question": " What are some of the clinical symptoms of toxoplasmosis? ",
        "answer": "\u00c2\u00a0  Fever, headache, and muscle aches",
        "options": [
            " Respiratory problems and cough ",
            " Seizures and epilepsy ",
            "\u00c2\u00a0  Fever, headache, and muscle aches",
            " Muscle pain and weakness ",
            "  Jaundice and liver failure"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 165,
        "question": "\u00c2\u00a0 What is the primary mode of transmission of Cryptosporidium parvum and Isospora belli? ",
        "answer": " Through contaminated water and food ",
        "options": [
            " Through contact with infected animals",
            " Through airborne droplets",
            " Through contaminated water and food ",
            "  Through mosquito bites",
            " Through sexual contact "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 166,
        "question": "What is a common treatment approach for toxoplasmosis caused by Toxoplasma gondii?",
        "answer": " Combination therapy using pyrimethamine and sulfadiazine",
        "options": [
            " Corticosteroids for inflammation reduction",
            " Combination therapy using pyrimethamine and sulfadiazine",
            " Immunotherapy with monoclonal antibodies",
            " Antiviral drugs targeting the parasite's replication",
            " Antibiotic therapy with penicillin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 167,
        "question": "Which organ system is frequently impacted by microsporidiosis?",
        "answer": " Digestive system",
        "options": [
            " Respiratory system",
            " Digestive system",
            " Circulatory system",
            " Nervous system",
            "Musculoskeletal system"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 168,
        "question": "How do microsporidia commonly enter the host's body? ",
        "answer": " Through skin contact with contaminated soil or water ",
        "options": [
            " Via airborne transmission from infected individuals ",
            " Consuming undercooked or contaminated food ",
            " Through skin contact with contaminated soil or water ",
            " Through insect bites, particularly from mosquitoes",
            " By direct contact with an infected person's respiratory secretions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 169,
        "question": "What is a commonly used treatment approach for microsporidiosis caused by microsporidia?",
        "answer": " Albendazole or nitazoxanide as effective anti-microsporidial agents",
        "options": [
            " Antifungal medications to eliminate the parasite",
            " Antibiotic therapy with penicillin",
            " Corticosteroids for inflammation reduction",
            " Albendazole or nitazoxanide as effective anti-microsporidial agents",
            " Antiviral drugs targeting the parasite's replication"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 170,
        "question": "Which characteristic is associated with Nematodes (Roundworms)?",
        "answer": " Elongated, cylindrical shape",
        "options": [
            " Elongated, cylindrical shape",
            " Tough, non-segmented body",
            " Segmented body structure with hooks or suckers",
            " Leaf-shaped or flattened worms",
            " Examples include Taeniasis and Fascioliasis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 171,
        "question": "Select the accurate feature related to Platyhelminthes:",
        "answer": " Trematodes possess oral and ventral suckers for attachment",
        "options": [
            " Cestodes (Tapeworms) possess segmented body structure with hooks or suckers",
            " Trematodes possess oral and ventral suckers for attachment",
            " Platyhelminthes include only Nematodes and Trematodes",
            " Nematodes (Roundworms) fall under Platyhelminthes due to their leaf-shaped structure",
            " Trematodes (Flukes) have an elongated, non-segmented body"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 172,
        "question": "How does a healthcare provider diagnose a pinworm infection?",
        "answer": "By collecting eggs around the anus",
        "options": [
            "With a blood test",
            "Skin biopsy",
            " By looking at the rash the infection makes",
            "Urine test",
            "By collecting eggs around the anus"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 173,
        "question": "Which of the following is true about the body structure of Taenia solium? ",
        "answer": "It has a flattened body shape",
        "options": [
            "It has a spherical body shape",
            "It has a triangular body shape",
            "It has a flattened body shape",
            "It has a cylindrical body shape",
            "It has an irregular body shap"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 174,
        "question": "Which of the following statements do define the segments of a tapeworm consisting primarily of eggs, which hang in bags as a long chain behind the head?",
        "answer": "proglottids",
        "options": [
            "scolexes",
            "sporocysts",
            "cercariae",
            "glycoalyxes",
            "proglottids"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 175,
        "question": "What is the feature of protonephridial system functions in cestodes?  ",
        "answer": "osmoregulation",
        "options": [
            "nervous co-ordination",
            "respiration",
            "reproduction",
            "digestion",
            "osmoregulation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 176,
        "question": "Which of the following is a causative agent of hydatid disease?",
        "answer": "Echinococcus granulosus",
        "options": [
            "Schistosoma mansoni",
            "Wuchereria bancrofti",
            "Trypanosoma cruzi",
            "Taenia solium",
            "Echinococcus granulosus"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 177,
        "question": "How could you possibly become infected with adult tapeworms?",
        "answer": "ingesting eggs in contaminated water",
        "options": [
            "being bitten by a mosquito",
            "direct penetration  through  cuticle",
            "ingesting eggs in contaminated water",
            "eating insufficiently cooked pork ",
            "all of the above are correct"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 178,
        "question": "Which of the following is the infective stage of Fasciolopsis buski? ",
        "answer": "Metacercariae",
        "options": [
            "Metacercariae",
            "Hydatid cyst",
            "Cercariae ",
            " Miracidia ",
            " Sporocysts "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 179,
        "question": "What is the most common mode of transmission of Fasciola hepatica to humans?",
        "answer": " Consumption of contaminated watercress",
        "options": [
            " Consumption of contaminated watercress",
            " Consumption of undercooked meat ",
            "Consumption of contaminated vegetables",
            "Skin contact with contaminated water ",
            " Inhalation of eggs "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 180,
        "question": "Through what way  Schistosomia spp. is  transmitted to humans?\u00c2\u00a0",
        "answer": "through contaminated food or water",
        "options": [
            "through respiratory droplets\u00c2\u00a0",
            "through contaminated food or water",
            "through insect bites ",
            "through sexual route ",
            "through skin contact with infected animals"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 181,
        "question": "Which one of the following statements about certain given animals is correct?",
        "answer": "Flat worms (Platyhelminthes) are coelomates",
        "options": [
            "Flat worms (Platyhelminthes) are coelomates",
            "Insects are pseudocoelomates",
            "Round worms  are pseudocoelomates",
            "Molluscs are acolomates",
            "Flat worms (Platyhelminthes) are coelomates"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 182,
        "question": "A person working in a rice paddy in Asia becomes infected with the liver fluke by? ",
        "answer": "swimming or wading in infected water, where the cercariae enter the skin",
        "options": [
            "eating infected snails",
            "swimming or wading in infected water, where the cercariae enter the skin",
            "drinking water contaminated with eggs",
            "direct penetration through cuticle.",
            "eating infected undercooked or uncooked fish,"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 183,
        "question": "Which vector does transmit Brugia malayi to humans? ",
        "answer": "Mosquitoe",
        "options": [
            "Lice ",
            "Sandfly",
            "Flea",
            "Tick",
            "Mosquitoe"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 184,
        "question": "History of mild intestinal distress, sleeplessness,\nitching, and anxiety is seen in preschool child attending play school. Which possible nematode is agent causing these manifestations?",
        "answer": "Enterobius vermicularis",
        "options": [
            "Wuchereria bancrofti",
            "Trichomonas vaginalis",
            "Necator americanus",
            "Enterobius vermicularis",
            "Ascaris lumbricoides"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 185,
        "question": "By what filarial worm is caused the  discrete   lesions  in   the  lung   parenchyma   resulting  in   well-circumscribed  circularnodules (coin lesions)?",
        "answer": "Dirofilaria immitis",
        "options": [
            "Dirofilaria repens",
            "\u00c2\u00a0Dirofilaria striata",
            "Dirofilaria immitis",
            "Dirofilaria ursi",
            "Dirofilaria tenuis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 186,
        "question": "Identify what is most common human source of Trichinella spiralis infection in human?",
        "answer": " Pork",
        "options": [
            " Pork",
            "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 Goat",
            "Beef",
            "Fish",
            "\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0 Dog"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 187,
        "question": "Which of the following arthropods is the primary vector for Russian spring-summer encephalitis? ",
        "answer": "Tick",
        "options": [
            "Lice ",
            "Mosquito",
            "Flea",
            "Mite",
            "Tick"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 188,
        "question": "The following pathogen is transmitted to humans through the bite of infected ticks during Lyme disease.What is the name the most likely pathogen?",
        "answer": "Borrelia burgdorferi",
        "options": [
            "Leptospira interrogans",
            "Bordetella pertusis\u00c2\u00a0",
            "Enterococcus faecalis",
            "Borrelia burgdorferi",
            "Borrelia buccalis\u00c2\u00a0"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 189,
        "question": "Which of the following diseases is NOT transmitted by ticks or mites? ",
        "answer": "Chikungunya ",
        "options": [
            "Rocky Mountain spotted fever ",
            "Q fever",
            "Scrub typhus ",
            "Chikungunya ",
            "Tularemia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 190,
        "question": "Which of the statements below is correct about Scabies?",
        "answer": "The infective stage is the egg",
        "options": [
            "Arthropods are vectors",
            "The infective stage is the egg",
            "Secondary bacterial infection is uncommon",
            "adult stage is infective stage ",
            "Nosocomial infection is a likelihood"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 191,
        "question": "How is associated most dangerous medical condition with ticks? ",
        "answer": "Allergic reaction ",
        "options": [
            "Lyme disaese ",
            "Tick paralysis ",
            "Tick born typhus ",
            "Allergic reaction ",
            "Plague "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 192,
        "question": "For what transmission is responsible Aedes aegypti mosquito?",
        "answer": "Yellow fever",
        "options": [
            "Yellow fever",
            "German measles",
            "AIDS",
            "Tick-borne relapsing fever",
            "Herpes simplex"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 193,
        "question": "Which species of mosquitoes is predominant vector of West Nile Virus (WNV)?",
        "answer": "Culex",
        "options": [
            "\u00c2\u00a0 Aedes\u00c2\u00a0\u00c2\u00a0",
            "Stomoxys",
            "\u00c2\u00a0 Anopheles",
            "Culex",
            "Ixodes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 194,
        "question": "Which of the following is not transmitted by a mosquito?",
        "answer": "Leishmania donovani",
        "options": [
            "Plasmodium vivax",
            "Wuchereria bancrofti",
            "Plasmodium falciparum",
            "Leishmania donovani",
            "Plasmodium ovale "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 195,
        "question": "Which of the following is a measure for preventing flea-borne diseases? ",
        "answer": "Keeping pets treated with flea preventive medication",
        "options": [
            "Washing hands with soap and water",
            "Vaccination ",
            "Keeping pets treated with flea preventive medication",
            "Properly cooking meat ",
            " Using insect repellent "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 196,
        "question": "What is the life cycle of fleas (order Siphonaptera)? ",
        "answer": "Egg, larva, pupa, adult ",
        "options": [
            "Egg, larva, nymph, adult",
            "Egg, larva, pupa, nymph, adult",
            "Egg, pupa, adult ",
            "Egg, larva, pupa, adult ",
            "Egg, nymph, adult"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 197,
        "question": "West Nile virus belongs to a group of viruses known as flaviviruses. How are these viruses spread?",
        "answer": "By mosquitoes",
        "options": [
            "By sneezing or coughing",
            "Through raw or undercooked meat",
            "Through contaminated water",
            "by flies ",
            "By mosquitoes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 198,
        "question": "During Plague disease which bacteria is transmitted by fleas ?",
        "answer": "Yersinia Pestis",
        "options": [
            "Borrelia burgdorferi ",
            "None of the above",
            "Clostridium",
            "Mycobacteria",
            "Yersinia Pestis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 199,
        "question": "How do lice get from person to person?",
        "answer": "Crawling",
        "options": [
            "Crawling",
            "Flying",
            "Walking ",
            "Skipping",
            "Jumping"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 200,
        "question": "A 5-years old boy presnts with multiple brown organisms attached to the base of his eyelashes. There is a suspicion of sexual abuse. Which of the following is the MOST likely organism? ",
        "answer": "Pthirus pubis ",
        "options": [
            "Pediculosis capitis ",
            "Pthirus pubis ",
            "Demodex folliculorum ",
            "pediculosis humanus corporis",
            "Borrelia burgdorferi "
        ]
    }
];
const start_btn = document.querySelector(".start_btn button");
const info_box = document.querySelector(".info_box");
const exit_btn = info_box.querySelector(".buttons .quit");
const continue_btn = info_box.querySelector(".buttons .restart");
const quiz_box = document.querySelector(".quiz_box");
const result_box = document.querySelector(".result_box");
const option_list = document.querySelector(".option_list");
const time_line = document.querySelector("header .time_line");
const timeText = document.querySelector(".timer .time_left_txt");
const timeCount = document.querySelector(".timer .timer_sec");

// if startQuiz button clicked
start_btn.onclick = ()=>{
    info_box.classList.add("activeInfo"); //show info box
}

// if exitQuiz button clicked
exit_btn.onclick = ()=>{
    info_box.classList.remove("activeInfo"); //hide info box
}

// if continueQuiz button clicked
continue_btn.onclick = ()=>{
    info_box.classList.remove("activeInfo"); //hide info box
    quiz_box.classList.add("activeQuiz"); //show quiz box
    showQuetions(0); //calling showQestions function
    queCounter(1); //passing 1 parameter to queCounter
    startTimer(15); //calling startTimer function
    startTimerLine(0); //calling startTimerLine function
}

let timeValue =  15;
let que_count = 0;
let que_numb = 1;
let userScore = 0;
let counter;
let counterLine;
let widthValue = 0;

const restart_quiz = result_box.querySelector(".buttons .restart");
const quit_quiz = result_box.querySelector(".buttons .quit");

// if restartQuiz button clicked
restart_quiz.onclick = ()=>{
    quiz_box.classList.add("activeQuiz"); //show quiz box
    result_box.classList.remove("activeResult"); //hide result box
    timeValue = 15; 
    que_count = 0;
    que_numb = 1;
    userScore = 0;
    widthValue = 0;
    showQuetions(que_count); //calling showQestions function
    queCounter(que_numb); //passing que_numb value to queCounter
    clearInterval(counter); //clear counter
    clearInterval(counterLine); //clear counterLine
    startTimer(timeValue); //calling startTimer function
    startTimerLine(widthValue); //calling startTimerLine function
    timeText.textContent = "Time Left"; //change the text of timeText to Time Left
    next_btn.classList.remove("show"); //hide the next button
}

// if quitQuiz button clicked
quit_quiz.onclick = ()=>{
    window.location.reload(); //reload the current window
}

const next_btn = document.querySelector("footer .next_btn");
const bottom_ques_counter = document.querySelector("footer .total_que");

// if Next Que button clicked
next_btn.onclick = ()=>{
    if(que_count < questions.length - 1){ //if question count is less than total question length
        que_count++; //increment the que_count value
        que_numb++; //increment the que_numb value
        showQuetions(que_count); //calling showQestions function
        queCounter(que_numb); //passing que_numb value to queCounter
        clearInterval(counter); //clear counter
        clearInterval(counterLine); //clear counterLine
        startTimer(timeValue); //calling startTimer function
        startTimerLine(widthValue); //calling startTimerLine function
        timeText.textContent = "Time Left"; //change the timeText to Time Left
        next_btn.classList.remove("show"); //hide the next button
    }else{
        clearInterval(counter); //clear counter
        clearInterval(counterLine); //clear counterLine
        showResult(); //calling showResult function
    }
}

// getting questions and options from array
function showQuetions(index){
    const que_text = document.querySelector(".que_text");

    //creating a new span and div tag for question and option and passing the value using array index
    let que_tag = '<span>'+ questions[index].numb + ". " + questions[index].question +'</span>';
    let option_tag = '<div class="option"><span>'+ questions[index].options[0] +'</span></div>'
    + '<div class="option"><span>'+ questions[index].options[1] +'</span></div>'
    + '<div class="option"><span>'+ questions[index].options[2] +'</span></div>'
    + '<div class="option"><span>'+ questions[index].options[3] +'</span></div>';
    que_text.innerHTML = que_tag; //adding new span tag inside que_tag
    option_list.innerHTML = option_tag; //adding new div tag inside option_tag
    
    const option = option_list.querySelectorAll(".option");

    // set onclick attribute to all available options
    for(i=0; i < option.length; i++){
        option[i].setAttribute("onclick", "optionSelected(this)");
    }
}
// creating the new div tags which for icons
let tickIconTag = '<div class="icon tick"><i class="fas fa-check"></i></div>';
let crossIconTag = '<div class="icon cross"><i class="fas fa-times"></i></div>';

//if user clicked on option
function optionSelected(answer){
    clearInterval(counter); //clear counter
    clearInterval(counterLine); //clear counterLine
    let userAns = answer.textContent; //getting user selected option
    let correcAns = questions[que_count].answer; //getting correct answer from array
    const allOptions = option_list.children.length; //getting all option items
    
    if(userAns == correcAns){ //if user selected option is equal to array's correct answer
        userScore += 1; //upgrading score value with 1
        answer.classList.add("correct"); //adding green color to correct selected option
        answer.insertAdjacentHTML("beforeend", tickIconTag); //adding tick icon to correct selected option
        console.log("Correct Answer");
        console.log("Your correct answers = " + userScore);
    }else{
        answer.classList.add("incorrect"); //adding red color to correct selected option
        answer.insertAdjacentHTML("beforeend", crossIconTag); //adding cross icon to correct selected option
        console.log("Wrong Answer");

        for(i=0; i < allOptions; i++){
            if(option_list.children[i].textContent == correcAns){ //if there is an option which is matched to an array answer 
                option_list.children[i].setAttribute("class", "option correct"); //adding green color to matched option
                option_list.children[i].insertAdjacentHTML("beforeend", tickIconTag); //adding tick icon to matched option
                console.log("Auto selected correct answer.");
            }
        }
    }
    for(i=0; i < allOptions; i++){
        option_list.children[i].classList.add("disabled"); //once user select an option then disabled all options
    }
    next_btn.classList.add("show"); //show the next button if user selected any option
}

function showResult(){
    info_box.classList.remove("activeInfo"); //hide info box
    quiz_box.classList.remove("activeQuiz"); //hide quiz box
    result_box.classList.add("activeResult"); //show result box
    const scoreText = result_box.querySelector(".score_text");
    if (userScore > 3){ // if user scored more than 3
        //creating a new span tag and passing the user score number and total question number
        let scoreTag = '<span>and congrats! 🎉, You got <p>'+ userScore +'</p> out of <p>'+ questions.length +'</p></span>';
        scoreText.innerHTML = scoreTag;  //adding new span tag inside score_Text
    }
    else if(userScore > 1){ // if user scored more than 1
        let scoreTag = '<span>and nice 😎, You got <p>'+ userScore +'</p> out of <p>'+ questions.length +'</p></span>';
        scoreText.innerHTML = scoreTag;
    }
    else{ // if user scored less than 1
        let scoreTag = '<span>and sorry 😐, You got only <p>'+ userScore +'</p> out of <p>'+ questions.length +'</p></span>';
        scoreText.innerHTML = scoreTag;
    }
}

function startTimer(time){
    counter = setInterval(timer, 1000);
    function timer(){
        timeCount.textContent = time; //changing the value of timeCount with time value
        time--; //decrement the time value
        if(time < 9){ //if timer is less than 9
            let addZero = timeCount.textContent; 
            timeCount.textContent = "0" + addZero; //add a 0 before time value
        }
        if(time < 0){ //if timer is less than 0
            clearInterval(counter); //clear counter
            timeText.textContent = "Time Off"; //change the time text to time off
            const allOptions = option_list.children.length; //getting all option items
            let correcAns = questions[que_count].answer; //getting correct answer from array
            for(i=0; i < allOptions; i++){
                if(option_list.children[i].textContent == correcAns){ //if there is an option which is matched to an array answer
                    option_list.children[i].setAttribute("class", "option correct"); //adding green color to matched option
                    option_list.children[i].insertAdjacentHTML("beforeend", tickIconTag); //adding tick icon to matched option
                    console.log("Time Off: Auto selected correct answer.");
                }
            }
            for(i=0; i < allOptions; i++){
                option_list.children[i].classList.add("disabled"); //once user select an option then disabled all options
            }
            next_btn.classList.add("show"); //show the next button if user selected any option
        }
    }
}

function startTimerLine(time){
    counterLine = setInterval(timer, 29);
    function timer(){
        time += 1; //upgrading time value with 1
        time_line.style.width = time + "px"; //increasing width of time_line with px by time value
        if(time > 549){ //if time value is greater than 549
            clearInterval(counterLine); //clear counterLine
        }
    }
}

function queCounter(index){
   
    let totalQueCounTag = '<span><p>'+ index +'</p> of <p>'+ questions.length +'</p> Questions</span>';
    bottom_ques_counter.innerHTML = totalQueCounTag;  
}
